History

TESLA 2022 - Present Buffalo, NY

Data Annotation Specialist/Analyst

Providing detailed labeling, analysis, and quality assurance assessment in support of the artificial intelligence deep learning network; continuously collaborating and troubleshooting to identify obstacles and find solutions to improve process, increasing quality outcomes and throughput; quickly pivoting to new projects, developing crossfunctionality to adeptly support mission and objectives

Boys & Girls Clubs of Buffalo 2016 - 2022 Buffalo, NY

• Data Manager/Analyst/Software Administrator

Leading the organization through the transition from one data system to another (COMET) without a conversion; building the Data Dept. from the ground up and the database content from scratch; designing structure; implementing checks and balances, protocol, procedure; maintaining daily system functionality and troubleshooting all software issues; conduit between organization and software owners; developing/constructing training material and facilitating training sessions for all user levels; teaching standards and practices to sustain data integrity; researching; assuring quality; generating reports

Holocaust Resource Center of Buffalo 2015 Buffalo, NY

• Interim Website Manager

Maintaining, designing, upgrading, editing, and implementing content and components to elevate UX to support the organization's longterm vision of strengthening its Web arm to benefit educators and community members; the website is to continuously evolve to serve as the nonprofit's hub of connectivity and learning

The Wild 2015 Portland, OR

Web Developer {apprenticeship}

Front end and back end R&D of interactive art installation, specifically mobile app MVP UI controller for M2M operation involving Kinect and from-scratch build out of back end for communication and storage; HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, MEAN stack, MQTT, npm, Yeoman, Bower, Gulp, Bitbucket; project details proprietary

Girls Inc. PNW 2014-2015 Gresham, OR / McMinnville, OR

Lead Facilitator of STEM Workshop on Coding

Leader of first STEM Camp for Girls at the Center for Advanced Learning, instructing Clear Creek students how to code; sessions include lessons on computers, programming, hardware, software, deconstructing/constructing/hooking up Raspberry Pis, introduction to the command line and how to build a project; HTML, CSS, Python

· Robotics Facilitator, Writer, and Researcher

Leader of LEGO robotics all-female team of youth participating in FLL competition; robot construction and block programming; developer of curriculum; author of Girls Inc. PNW LEGO Robotics facilitator handbook and team member workbook

ETRI Journal / ETRI 2012-2014 Daejeon, South Korea

Editor and Researcher

Editing, writing, research, and correspondence for international electronics and telecommunications science journal; all work written by non-native English speakers from a variety of countries; rewriting of complex, high-tech material on topics such as microelectronics, computer software, big data, information security, and 3D technology, including virtual reality (VR) and augmented reality (AR); design and implementation of transparent internal communication system, increasing efficiency of editorial process and elevating quality of the journal

Tester and Demonstrator {special project}

Special project consultant for GenieTalk, an Android automatic language translation app; key demonstrator of the technology, including high profile demonstration for the Ministry of Knowledge Economy, part of the Cabinet of the Republic of Korea

Avalon English 2011-2012 Daejeon, South Korea

English Teacher

Writing, reading, listening, and speaking courses; quarterly rotation of 70-80 elementary, middle, and high school students, beginner through advanced levels; writing workbooks; creating supplemental materials daily

parenting.com 2010 New York, NY

Project Coordinator and Editor

Managing a complex campaign for the online division of Parenting magazine; establishing contacts; recruiting participants; developing and maintaining business relationships; securing legal documentation from around the world; writing, editing, research, and correspondence; procurement of \$50,000 in prize donations; completion of project before hard deadline

Summary

Data Manager and Analyst with extensive experience in the information technology (IT), research, and publishing industries. Self-driven IT professional highly skilled in investigative research, applied logic, analysis, writing, editing, technical documentation, project coordination, and data management. Formal education includes Web/tech specialization in design and databases, a Master of Arts (M.A.) in Film Studies, a Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) in English with a minor in Media Study, and certification in TESOL/TESL/TEFL, specializing in English grammar.

Education

Epicodus Web Design & Development / Databases Portland, OR

State University of New York M.A.: Film Studies Buffalo, NY

State University of New York B.A.: English (minor: Media Study), cum laude Buffalo, NY

Further information, including history items and references, furnished upon request.